Adriana Niño

Full Stack Developer

Austin, TX	737.328.3496	ninadri.dev@gmail.com	<u>LinkedIn</u>	<u>GitHub</u>	<u>Portfolio</u>
------------	--------------	-----------------------	-----------------	---------------	------------------

I'm a seasoned customer service expert on a journey to become a coding aficionado! I'm an artist at heart and being able to incorporate that into the tech world has been most exciting for me. Though I'm new to coding, the Full Stack Development Bootcamp at the University of Texas at Austin has shown me endless possibilities, and I hope to explore them with your company.

EDUCATION

The Coding Boot Camp - University of Texas at Austin

Austin Web Development Boot Camp

Rigorous 24-week full stack development course.

Austin, TX

Feb 2024- Aug 2024

Udemy

The Ultimate React Course 2024: React, Next.js, Redux & More
The Complete JavaScript Course 2024: From Zero to Expert!

Ongoing

SKILLS

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, iQuery, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, The DOM, APIs, JSON, AJAX

Backend: SQL, MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node, NoSQL, Testing

Soft Skills: Resourceful, Creative, Leadership, Problem Solving, Adaptable, Organization, Motivated

PROJECTS

Weather Search | Front-End | Repo | Deployed

A user-friendly weather dashboard designed for seamless exploration of current and upcoming weather forecasts for cities worldwide. Developed a weather dashboard with **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, and **Server-Side APIs** that utilizes a 5-Day Weather Forecast API. Implemented a feature that saves the last searched cities as buttons for easy access and quick reference.

My Blog | Front-End | Repo | Deployed

A platform enabling users to effortlessly craft blog posts, providing them the flexibility to either preserve or discard their creations at their discretion. Developed a content form with **HTML**, **CSS**, **Web APIs**, and **JavaScript** that renders a dynamic blog post and integrated a light/dark mode toggle for enhanced user experience

SVG Logo Maker | Back-End | *Repo*

This command-line app allows freelance web developers to generate a simple logo by entering text, text color, shape, and shape color, resulting in a custom SVG file named logo.svg. Developed a command-line

application utilizing **Objected-Oriented Programming** and **Node.js** that generates an SVG file based on user responses to a series of questions.

E-Commerce Back End | Back-End | *Repo*

A back-end system for an e-commerce website. Developed a back-end platform for an e-commerce website using **Express.js**, **PostgreSQL**, and **Sequelize**, allowing a manager to connect to the database, create and seed it, start the server, and perform CRUD operations via API routes

Employee Tracker System | Back-End | Repo

A command-line application for business owners to view and manage departments, roles, and employees, enabling better organization and planning. Developed a backend application with **SQL** for business managers to add employees to their database, assign to a manager, update their department and role, add a role, add a salary and view all the above in a table.

EXPERIENCE

Heartland Dental – Leander, TX - August 2023-Current

Business Associate

Greet and welcome patients to create a positive first impression while managing front office duties, including phone calls, emails, and mail. Utilize Dentrix for scheduling and patient records, schedule and confirm appointments for multiple providers, and file and follow up on insurance claims. Verify benefits through insurance portals, explain coverage, post payments, and process accounts receivables. Review treatment plan fees and payment options with patients.

H-E-B – Lakeway, TX - January 2021- August 2023

Healthy Living Lead

Supervise and train department employees to meet performance standards, plan engaging displays to enhance the customer experience, and foster strong customer relationships by understanding their health goals. Collaborate with other departments, analyze sales data to forecast future projects, and develop innovative ideas to improve team and department performance.

Healthy Living Representative - June 2019 - December 2020

Received "Partner of The Week" for exceptional performance shortly after joining, contributing to the success of both the previous and new departments. Created personalized experiences by interacting with customers. Conducted daily inventory inspections to inform ordering forecasts. Coordinated with management to stay updated on daily changes and ensure seamless operations.

Curbside – Austin, TX - Jan 2019 – June 2019

Fulfilled customers' online orders by coordinating with specialized departments to obtain specific products. Reviewed customer notes to update any changes and made outbound calls to inform members. Conducted daily audits of completed orders to identify and resolve any discrepancies.